in this Tasker session we are going to
talk about the action mode buffer now we
have briefly spoken about the action
mode buffer in our previous session when
we were discussing about other action
modes like verify
constraint and uh also select right so
what exactly is a buffer
in Tosca this term buffer is used to
refer to values which can be stored
temporarily in Tosca commander and then
they can be used again
so this helps you to store values which
you want to verify later in a different
test case or in later part of your test
cases right so it's like a global
variable you can say in uh in terms of
programming languages it acts as a
global variable which can store some
values and you can use it throughout
your test cases okay
these values can either be static or
dynamic
and there are different ways to buffer
values in Tosca one of the ways is the
action mode buffer and which we are
going to see in this particular
demonstration
also once you create this buffer values
they are available or stored in settings
under the Tosca engine right so if you
go to settings engine you will see there
is a folder called buffer and once you
create a buffer
um or once you buffer any particular
value that particular value will be
stored on under this folder okay so for
creating a buffer you need a buffer name
and then a particular value which will
be stored in that particular variable
which is the buffer name okay so both
will be displayed here under buffer with
the name and a value
so we'll see that when after we create a
particular buffer value and then we'll
come back to the screen and we'll see
that it is stored uh in this particular
folder okay
so to understand how this action mode
buffer Works let's pick up a scenario
okay so I am on this demo webshop and my
particular scenario is once I go into
this login and I log in with my email
and password okay and then I click on
login I come to this page on this home
page my email is displayed right and
that tells me that or that's a
verification step telling me that I have
logged in successfully okay I can either
verify this or I can also verify a log
out but for this particular scenario
let's verify that this particular email
is displayed here okay
now it's a very common scenario which
you will be probably automating in
almost every application where you are
logging in and logging out so to verify
your login test case you will probably
need this verification step right so
let's see how we can use the action mode
buffer in order to perform this
particular scenario okay
so what I have done already in my Tosca
is I've already created a particular
module or different modules for
performing this particular scenario okay
so I have got all the modules like
logout with username and log out and log
in where we'll enter all the information
for that particular user and the
register page which currently we are not
using and the headers where we have got
the login link okay so we'll be using
all these modules to create a test case
and in that test case we'll also use the
action mode buffer okay
so I have already a folder called actual
modes inside this I'm going to create
another test case and I'm going to name
it verify buffer
okay
so this is my test case name you can
name it anything but let's go ahead with
this
and then I'm going to add my test steps
so the first step is to click on the
login link okay so for that I will have
to add the headers module okay and here
I have the login link so I'm going to
click on this and the action mode will
be input okay let's rename this so to
click login
and my next module is to
enter all the user information like the
email password right in the login page
so let's add the login information here
and here we'll be entering the username
and password
okay
and here we'll enter the password and
then we'll click on the login link
okay so that's our login
and then we will do
another test step where we will be
verifying or we'll be buffering our
values okay so for this we'll be using
the logout module
okay so we have got two controls
username and logout we can verify any of
them but we'll be going ahead with the
username or email okay
so first what we are going to do is to
buffer this particular username or email
right which is present on the
application
so for this we are going to use the
action mode buffer
okay
so once you select the action mode
buffer uh the value would be entered
automatically it will just copy the
control name but you can always change
it okay so I'm going to use the buffer
name as email
okay so what's going to happen here uh
once we select action one buffer it's
um we have to enter a buffer name here
which is the email and the value of this
particular control okay will be buffered
into this particular email buffer name
okay so this is like a variable and the
value of this control would be stored
inside this
and let's rename our test steps so so
that we can better understand what's
going on here so we'll say buffer
username
okay and then the next step is to verify
the username so again we'll add the
logout module here
and we'll name it verify username
and this time around we are going to
verify or use the action mode verify
okay and here we are going to now
call that buffer which we have stored
earlier right so we are going to reuse
that particular value in this particular
step okay so for that again curly braces
okay it's a dynamic expression and then
you need to type B B means buffer all
right it shows you the description so
Returns the value stored in the
specified buffer okay
and then you have to say bracket and
then you have to type the buffer name
which you have used earlier right so it
is email we already know that
so this is our value which it should be
verified against okay
and then finally what we are going to do
is we are going to click on the logout
link so again the logout modules
and this time around we are going to
click on the logout link right so that's
my whole scenario you can see first I'll
click on login I will enter the
information required and then login the
user and then I am going to buffer the
username which is present on the
application
and then I'm going to verify that
against
uh my actual username okay
uh okay and then I'm going to click on
the logout link
so this is our whole scenario you can
see we are using the action mode buffer
and the action mode verify
in order to buffer a particular value
and then use it uh later to verify uh
that particular value okay
foreign so let's go ahead and run this
now Okay so let me click on logout so
that we are on the uh home page
and let's go ahead and run this in
scratchbook
so as you can see uh it executed all the
steps
um it's also present in your results
okay
the two steps which we are interested is
in buffer username and verify username
so the buffer username you can see here
it is saying a buffer with name email
has been set to this particular value
okay so this was the value or the inner
text right for this particular control
which was stored in this particular
email
okay
and then uh what we did we that was our
expected value right which we stored in
the buffer and then we are actually
verifying it with our actual value okay
so this is one small example how you can
use the action mode buffer it can be
used in different scenarios like if you
want to verify some table values you
buffer those values either in the
database or in the web application and
then you use those buffer values and
verify it against the application or the
database right so there are many
scenarios where you can use this it's
very useful
um whenever you are trying to automate
different scenarios okay
so the last thing uh which we want to
verify is whether this buffer value was
stored
um in the Tosca Commander okay so I told
you that we can see that under settings
and under engine
so this buffer value with the name email
and the username in the value column is
added under this buffer okay
so this is a temporary uh kind of
variable which can be used in your test
cases to perform different steps right
we'll look at some of the other action
modes like weight on in our coming up
session